finalsite.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy | Finalsite

_Updated 03/28/19_

> **_If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at  _**[ ** _https://feedback-form. truste.com/watchdog/request_**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "Opens in new window.") ** _._**

This privacy policy describes how Active Internet Technologies dba “Finalsite” collects and uses the personal information you provide on our website: www.finalsite.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

The use of information collected through our Service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the Service for which the Client has engaged Active Internet Technologies. Active Internet Technologies participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Active Internet Technologies is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, the United Kingdom and Switzerland respectively, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Active Internet Technologies is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Active Internet Technologies complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, the United Kingdom and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Active Internet Technologies is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Active Internet Technologies may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider, (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. Under certain conditions, [more fully described on the Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint "Opens in new window."), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Information Collection And Use**

**Emails and Web Forms**  
We collect information from users of our site and client portal such as name, email, school information, and phone number when you request demos or contact us. Personal information that you provide by email or web forms will be used only for such purposes as are described at the point of collection (for example on a web form), such as to send information to you or respond to your questions or comments. If you provide contact information, Finalsite staff or its contractors may contact you to clarify your comment or question, or to learn about your level of interest in, or satisfaction with our services. We do not share or sell any personal information to third parties except as described in this privacy policy.

In the event Finalsite goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our website for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

**Orders**  
If you register for a Finalsite event, we request certain personal information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and school information) and, for chargeable events, financial information (such as credit card number and expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes for event registration or to contact you if we have difficulty processing your order.

**Testimonials**  
Our client contracts include client permission to post testimonials, both written and video, on our website. Permission to display client reference information (name, school, phone number) is obtained from our clients prior to displaying them on our site. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [marketing@finalsite.com](mailto:education@finalsite.com).

**Blog**  
Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [marketing@finalsite.com](mailto:marketing@finalsite.com "Opens in new window."). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Surveys**  
Occasionally we may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate we will request certain personal information from you. Participation in these surveys is entirely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to improve our Finalsite services and product offerings.

**Share/Email-a-Page**  
If you choose to use the +Share link available at the bottom of most site pages, you will be invoking the AddThis tool which is a third party product enabling you to easily send our website links to other sites or to email a page link to a friend. All personal information (such as name and email address) you enter here is covered by the AddThis privacy policy, available at <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>.

**Service Providers**  
We use other third parties such as a credit card processor to bill you for goods and services. For instance, when you register for an event we will share your credit card information with our payment processor as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for promotional purposes.

**Information Collected And Stored Automatically**  
If you do nothing during your visit but browse through our website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically using cookies and log files. We use this information to help make our site more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to our site, and the types of technology they use.

**Log Files**  
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base. We do not link this automatically collected data to personal information.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

Active Internet Technologies and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.

We partner with third parties to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union, [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Communications From Finalsite**

**Customer Service**  
Based upon the personal information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request or in which you express interest, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

**Opt-out of Special Offers and Updates**  
We will occasionally send you information on products, services, and promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. If you no longer wish to receive our promotional email communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each newsletter, by emailing us at education@finalsite.com, or calling us at 860.289.3507. Our portal users may opt out by clicking on the “My Account” button in the upper left corner of the portal home page, and selecting “My Subscriptions”. Then under “Current Subscriptions” click on “Email Mailing List Settings”.

**Ask the Community and Share an Idea portals**

For users of our Ask the Community and Share an Idea portals, your data is submitted to our partners aha.io and Slack. Additionally, we may copy your data into other tools as we act upon your suggestions.  We have agreements in place with these companies to ensure that they will only use your data as instructed by Finalsite.  They will not share your data with any entity other than Finalsite and will not use it for their business. 

Your data will be used to display your posts and responses on the portal, and to send you emails regarding your posts and responses.  Finalsite may contact you directly regarding your posts and responses.  All emails have unsubscribe links and you can unsubscribe from receiving emails on the posts form.

Your data will be retained for as long as we deem it useful for the portals, at which time it will be removed from the portal.  Data submitted to Slack will be retained for 1 year.

You may withdraw from participation in the portals by either making a support request at [https://www.finalsitesupport.com](https://www.finalsitesupport.com/) or sending an email to [privacy@finalsite.com](mailto:privacy@finalsite.com)

For our European Union based users.  Our lawful basis of processing is “Legitimate Interests.” 

**Updating Personal Information**

Upon request Active Internet Technologies will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. To request this information, please contact us by phone or postal mail at the contact information listed at the end of this policy. We will respond to these requests within a reasonable time frame.

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or delete your information by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed at the end of this policy. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

Active Internet Technologies collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients.

Active Internet Technologies has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Active Internet Technologies’ Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable time frame.

**Links To Other Sites**  
Our policy discloses the privacy practices for the Finalsite website. However, we do provide links to other websites. When you leave [www.finalsite.com](http://www.finalsite.com/) you will go to sites outside of our control. These external sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. The privacy policies and procedures described here for Finalsite do not apply to any external links. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of any site you link to from ours, especially if you share any personal information. Be informed. You are the person best qualified to protect your own privacy.

**Data Retention**  
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at privacy@finalsite.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Legal Disclaimer**  
We reserve the right to disclose your personal information, as well as personal information we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client, as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

**Security**  
The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at education@finalsite.com.

**Changes In This Privacy Policy**  
If we decide to change our privacy practices, we will post those changes to this privacy policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate, to inform you of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we change how we use your personal information we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

**Contact Us**  
Feel free to contact us regarding this privacy policy at [privacy@finalsite.com](mailto:education@finalsite.com), by telephone at 860.289.3507, or by postal mail at Finalsite, 655 Winding Brook Drive, Glastonbury, Connecticut 06033.
